# Tajmir khan

Date of birth: 03/02/1994 | Nationality: Pakistani | Phone: (+92) 3085299701 (Mobile) | Email:

tajmirkhan515@gmail.com | Email: tajmirkhan@cs.gau.edu.pk | LinkedIn:

www.linkedin.com/in/tajmir-khan-a60a6b174 | **Github:** https://github.com/Tajmirkhan515/ | **Portfolio:** 

https://tajmirkhan515.github.io/ Address: 23370, Rustam, Pakistan (Home)

## ABOUT MYSELF

As an NLP researcher have good publications in reputable journals and substantial teaching experience. Recently, have taught Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) Lab at Quaid E Azam University and have strong coding skills, showcased in my GitHub repository. Additionally, I have experience in blogging (OOP). Besides, I participated in international hackathons. Looking ahead, I am keen on continuing my research and publishing in esteemed journals.

### EDUCATION AND TRAINING

08/2019 - 19/04/2022 Islamabad, Pakistan

M.PHIL COMPUTER SCIENCE Quaid-i-Azam University, Islamabad

Address 45320, Islamabad, Pakistan | Website <a href="https://qau.edu.pk/">https://qau.edu.pk/</a> | Field of study Computer Science | Final grade 3.42/4 |

Thesis Multimedia Vertical Web Search Query Modification Framework using Relevance Feedback Approach

01/11/2015 - 20/03/2018 Nowshera, Pakistan

MCS COMPUTER SCIENCE Northern University

Address 24110, Nowshera, Pakistan | Website http://www.northern.edu.pk/ | Final grade 3.45/4 |

**Thesis** Tailor Management System (Android App)

### WORK EXPERIENCE

01/01/2024 - CURRENT Islamabad, Pakistan

LAB INSTRUCTOR OF OBJECT-ORIENTED PROGRAMMING (OOP) QUAID-I-AZAM UNIVERSITY

- Taught Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) lab sessions to a class of 50 BSCS students.
- Implemented and demonstrated OOP concepts through practical exercises using Visual Studio.
- Evaluate the students using tasks, correct their errors, and provide feedback to enhance learning.

30/09/2017 - 29/08/2019 Peshawar, Pakistan

# **APPLICATION DEVELOPER LEAP APP SOLUTION**

I worked as an Android developer.

### PUBLICATIONS

2024

End-to-end pseudo relevance feedback based vertical web search queries recommendation approach

Journal: Multimedia Tools and Applications - Springer;

**Impact Factor 3.6** 

Tajmir Khan 1\* Umer Rashid 1, Abdur Rehman Khan 2

Link <a href="https://github.com/Tajmirkhan515/Queries-Recommendation">https://github.com/Tajmirkhan515/Queries-Recommendation</a>

2024

End-to-end pseudo relevance feedback-based vertical web search queries recommendation Software

Journal: Multimedia Tools and Applications - Springer 2024;

**Impact Factor 4** 

Tajmir khan, Umer Rashid, and Abdur Rehman.

2024

# Faceted Aggregated Multimedia Search Results Exploration Framework [Under Evaluation]

Abdur Rehman Khan, Tajmir khan, Umer Rashid

# DIGITAL SKILLS

python | c++ | Android Developement (Android Studio, Java) | SQL (MySQL) | machine learning | Natural Language Processing (NLP) | java

## INTERNATIONAL HACKATHONS

19/07/2024 - 21/07/2024

### llama-3-hackathon

Recently submitted a complete project (VisisonAI) app developed using Python and Django. In this project, I worked as an AI/ML engineer and was responsible for integrating the entire application. Similarly, uploaded my GitHub repository.

**Links** <a href="https://lablab.ai/event/llama-3-ai-hackathon/algorithm-alchemist/vision-assist-ai">https://lablab.ai/event/llama-3-ai-hackathon/algorithm-alchemist/vision-assist-ai</a> | <a href="https://lablab.ai/u/@tajmirkhan515923/cm0fh47v0008ve7ih12mw6dxf">https://lablab.ai/event/llama-3-ai-hackathon/algorithm-alchemist/vision-assist-ai</a> | <a href="https://lablab.ai/u/@tajmirkhan515923/cm0fh47v0008ve7ih12mw6dxf">https://lablab.ai/u/@tajmirkhan515923/cm0fh47v0008ve7ih12mw6dxf</a>

26/07/2024 - CURRENT

### **Falcon Hackathon**

Actively engaged in the Falcon international hackathon, focusing on AI/ML and learning Streamlit. Additionally, I am leading the project and overseeing its development.

# RECOMMENDATIONS

Dr. Umer Rashid Supervisor

Dr. Umer Rashid is an Assistant Professor at the School of Computer Science at the Quaid-i-Azam University, Islamabad, Pakistan. His research interest is in Multimedia Information retrieval.

**Email** <u>umerrashid@gau.edu.pk</u> | **Phone** (+92) 5190642012

Link <a href="http://cs.gau.edu.pk/profiles/umer.htm">http://cs.gau.edu.pk/profiles/umer.htm</a>

Dr. Rabeeh Ayaz Abbasi Head of the Department

Dr. Rabeeh Ayaz Abbasi is an Associate Professor at the School of Computer Science at the Quaid-i-Azam University, Islamabad, Pakistan. His research Social Network Analysis.

Email <a href="mailto:rabbasi@gau.edu.pk">rabbasi@gau.edu.pk</a> | Phone (+92) 5190642050

Link <a href="http://cs.qau.edu.pk/profiles/rabeeh.htm">http://cs.qau.edu.pk/profiles/rabeeh.htm</a>